RYAN RENFREW MEDIA PROFESSIONAL

ryanrenfrew@gmail.com www.ryanrenfrew.net (562) 296-7779



Writer/Director | 2011 - 2013

PERSONAL INFO

I am a media professional specializing in video production and graphic design. I have extensive experience with non-linear editing programs such as Adobe Premiere and Final Cut Pro. I am also trained in camera operation, lighting technique and the use of Adobe Photoshop and InDesign.

As a team manager and short-film director I have streamlined workflows and improved team efficiency. I hope to apply and refine these skills as a member of your organization.

EDUCATION

B.A. Philosophy 2013

University of California, Santa Barbara Dean's Honors, 4 Quarters

SKILLS

Premiere	*	*	*	*	*
Audition	*	*	*	*	
After Effects	*	*	*		
Photoshop	*	*	*	*	
InDesign	*	*	*	*	
Final Cut Pro 7	*	*	*	*	
Lighting/Camera	*	*	*	*	
Avid	*	*			
WordPress	*	*	*		

PROJECTS

SHORT FILMS

Delta-V (2013), 30 minutes Winner:

Sherrill C. Corwin Award for Best Short Screenplay Best Cinematography

The Misinformant (2012), 16 minutes The Creative Process (2011), 5 minutes

- Worked with the camera department to design lighting setups, create shot lists, and operate cameras
- Edited footage, established production workflow, mastered audio, and encoded projects for delivery
- Assembled a cast and crew through interviews and auditions
- Rehearsed with actors to ensure cohesive, consistent performances
- Managed the set to maximize efficiency, morale, and creativity

RADIO BROADCAST

Co-Host | 2013

The Picture Show with Bianca Beltran and Ryan Renfrew

- A weekly talk radio show about films and the entertainment industry on KCSB 91.9 FM Fridays from 12:00PM to 1:00PM
- Facilitated unscripted discussion and debate on a variety of topics relating to film and television
- Hosted guests and interviewed local filmmakers
- Managed live studio broadcast

EMPLOYMENT

WARNER BROS. STUDIOS

Tour Guide | 2013-Present

- Conduct tours of studio production facilities, production sound stages, exterior sets, and other areas of interest
- Present an unscripted and comprehensive description of historical and current information about the studio as well as various filmmaking techniques
- Serve as a public-facing employee for the studio, ensuring a memorable, interesting and entertaining experience for each of our guests

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA

Head Grader | 2011-2013

- Hired and managed a team of 15 graders and oversaw the grades for a class of 650 students
- Redesigned the exam grading system, resulting in improved efficiency and fewer clerical errors
- Designed test keys for use in grading written exams
- Met with students to answer questions regarding their exam scores and delineate our grading methodologies
- Maintained detailed records of course grades in order to facilitate the quick resolution of discrepancies